<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  
    <title type="text" xml:lang="en">Takehiro Mouri - Ruby on Rails Developer</title>
    <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/atom.xml"/>
  
  <link href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/"/>
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/</id>
  <updated>2016-04-02T14:53:21Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Takehiro Mouri</name>
    <email>takehiromouri@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <rights type="text">Copyright © 2016 Takehiro Mouri. All rights reserved.</rights>
  
  <entry>
  <title type="text">How to Count Belonging Objects More Efficiently in Rails</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/How-to-Count-Belonging-Objects-More-Efficiently-in-Rails.html" />
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/How-to-Count-Belonging-Objects-More-Efficiently-in-Rails</id>
  <published>2016-04-01T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2016-04-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>A lot of times when writing rails apps, you face a situation where you have to count the number of child objects a parent object has.</p>

<p>For instance, let&rsquo;s say we have a <code>User</code> model and a <code>Comment</code> model where <code>User</code> <code>has_many :comments</code> and <code>Comment</code> <code>belongs_to :user</code>.</p>

<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">User</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="no">ActiveRecord</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">Base</span>
  <span class="n">has_many</span> <span class="ss">:comments</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">Comment</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="no">ActiveRecord</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">Base</span>
  <span class="n">belongs_to</span> <span class="ss">:user</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>What do we do when we want to count the number of comments that a <code>User</code> has? A lot of times, it would look something like this:</p>

<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">comments</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">count</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>This is all fine, if you&rsquo;re only using it once in a while.
But say we need to query the database often for the number of comments that a <code>User</code> has.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s see what the performance is like when using <code>user.comments.count</code>.
In an example app I created with the same models as above, I tested this out with a <code>user</code> with 225 <code>comments</code>:</p>

<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">irb<span class="o">(</span>main<span class="o">)</span>:015:0&gt; User.first.comments.count
  User Load <span class="o">(</span>0.3ms<span class="o">)</span>  SELECT  <span class="s2">&quot;users&quot;</span>.<em> FROM <span class="s2">&quot;users&quot;</span>  ORDER BY <span class="s2">&quot;users&quot;</span>.<span class="s2">&quot;id&quot;</span> ASC LIMIT 1
   <span class="o">(</span>0.4ms<span class="o">)</span>  SELECT COUNT<span class="o">(</span></em><span class="o">)</span> FROM <span class="s2">&quot;comments&quot;</span> WHERE <span class="s2">&quot;comments&quot;</span>.<span class="s2">&quot;user_id&quot;</span> <span class="o">=</span> ?  <span class="o">[[</span><span class="s2">&quot;user_id&quot;</span>, 1<span class="o">]]</span>
<span class="o">=</span>&gt; 225</code></pre></figure></p>

<p>Notice how the <code>comments</code> are queried with a COUNT(*) query. If we were to query 100 users at once for <code>comments.count</code>, it would be a big load for the database.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s how we can avoid the COUNT(*) query and improve performance:</p>

<h2>Introducing <code>counter_cache</code></h2>


<p>Instead of querying <code>comments</code>, we can just store the number of comments a user has in the <code>User</code> table and get the number of comments without any SQL query.</p>

<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">AddCommentCounterToUser</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="no">ActiveRecord</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">Migration</span>
  <span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">change</span>
    <span class="n">add_column</span> <span class="ss">:users</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="ss">:comments_count</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="ss">:integer</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="ss">default</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="mi">0</span>
  <span class="k">end</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>In order for <code>counter_cache</code> to work, we need to create a database column that ends with <code>_count</code>. So here, we have created a <code>comments_count</code> column that will store the number of comments inside.</p>

<p>After we run the migration, we want to initially update the <code>comments_count</code> for each <code>User</code>.</p>

<p>We can do this by creating a rake file, or manually running code in the console:</p>

<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="no">User</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">reset_column_information</span>
<span class="no">User</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">all</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">each</span> <span class="k">do</span> <span class="o">|</span><span class="n">user</span><span class="o">|</span>
  <span class="no">User</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">update_counters</span> <span class="n">user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">id</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="ss">comments_count</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">comments</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">length</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p><code>reset_column_information</code> resets all the cached information about columns, and will be reloaded before the code below runs.</p>

<p>Now after we run this code, we see that the correct number of comments are stored in the user object:</p>

<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">irb<span class="o">(</span>main<span class="o">)</span>:005:0&gt; <span class="nv">user</span>
<span class="o">=</span>&gt; <span class="c">#&lt;User id: 1, name: &quot;Bob&quot;, created_at: &quot;2016-04-01 06:51:53&quot;, updated_at: &quot;2016-04-01 07:37:39&quot;, comments_count: 225&gt;</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>One more thing we need to do:</p>

<p>In the <code>Comment</code> model, we need to set <code>counter_cache: true</code>.</p>

<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">Comment</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="no">ActiveRecord</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">Base</span>
  <span class="n">belongs_to</span> <span class="ss">:user</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="ss">counter_cache</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="kp">true</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>This will increment and decrement the <code>comments_count</code> column automatically in <code>User</code> whenever a comment is created or deleted.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s test this out:</p>

<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">irb<span class="o">(</span>main<span class="o">)</span>:006:0&gt; user.comments.create<span class="o">(</span>text: <span class="s2">&quot;hello&quot;</span><span class="o">)</span>
   <span class="o">(</span>1.7ms<span class="o">)</span>  begin transaction
  SQL <span class="o">(</span>1.9ms<span class="o">)</span>  INSERT INTO <span class="s2">&quot;comments&quot;</span> <span class="o">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;text&quot;</span>, <span class="s2">&quot;user_id&quot;</span>, <span class="s2">&quot;created_at&quot;</span>, <span class="s2">&quot;updated_at&quot;</span><span class="o">)</span> VALUES <span class="o">(</span>?, ?, ?, ?<span class="o">)</span>  <span class="o">[[</span><span class="s2">&quot;text&quot;</span>, <span class="s2">&quot;hello&quot;</span><span class="o">]</span>, <span class="o">[</span><span class="s2">&quot;user_id&quot;</span>, 1<span class="o">]</span>, <span class="o">[</span><span class="s2">&quot;created_at&quot;</span>, <span class="s2">&quot;2016-04-02 18:27:36.897717&quot;</span><span class="o">]</span>, <span class="o">[</span><span class="s2">&quot;updated_at&quot;</span>, <span class="s2">&quot;2016-04-02 18:27:36.897717&quot;</span><span class="o">]]</span>
  SQL <span class="o">(</span>0.6ms<span class="o">)</span>  UPDATE <span class="s2">&quot;users&quot;</span> SET <span class="s2">&quot;comments_count&quot;</span> <span class="o">=</span> COALESCE<span class="o">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;comments_count&quot;</span>, 0<span class="o">)</span> + <span class="m">1</span> WHERE <span class="s2">&quot;users&quot;</span>.<span class="s2">&quot;id&quot;</span> <span class="o">=</span> ?  <span class="o">[[</span><span class="s2">&quot;id&quot;</span>, 1<span class="o">]]</span>
   <span class="o">(</span>5.9ms<span class="o">)</span>  commit <span class="nv">transaction</span>
<span class="o">=</span>&gt; <span class="c">#&lt;Comment id: 225, user_id: 1, text: &quot;hello&quot;, created_at: &quot;2016-04-02 18:27:36&quot;, updated_at: &quot;2016-04-02 18:27:36&quot;&gt;</span>
irb<span class="o">(</span>main<span class="o">)</span>:007:0&gt; user.comments_count
<span class="o">=</span>&gt; 226</code></pre></figure></p>

<p>Awesome! As you can see, it properly incremented the <code>comments_count</code> from <code>225</code> to <code>226</code>.</p>

<p>Using <code>counter_cache</code> can increase performance when you are trying to display, for instance, many users and their comment counts. Instead of making a bunch of COUNT(*) queries, by using <code>counter_cache</code>, you can access the same information by just accessing a column in the <code>User</code> table.</p>
 ]]></content>
</entry>


  <entry>
  <title type="text">My Approach to Achieving Deep Focus</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/Entering-Zen-Mode.html" />
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/Entering-Zen-Mode</id>
  <published>2016-03-30T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2016-03-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>If you ever want to get good at something, I’m a firm believer of going into what I like to call <strong>“Zen Mode”</strong>. Some people call it <i>“the state of flow”</i>, some people call it <i>“deep focus”</i>, other people call it other things.</p>

<p>I get the most things done when I’m in my Zen Mode.</p>

<p><strong>If I’m not in my Zen Mode, I’m distracted, I’m unfocused, and I’m wasting my time.</strong></p>

<h1>First I ask myself: Do I like what I’m doing?</h1>

<p>First things first, I find that <strong>if I don’t like what I’m learning or doing, I’m never able to enter Zen Mode.</strong></p>

<p>So if I’m trying to enter Zen Mode in something I just don’t enjoy or care about, then <strong>I’m a strong believer in picking up something else instead.</strong></p>

<h1>Locking Myself Up = Deep Focus</h1>

<p>One of my friends who I consider to be a genius mathematician once told me this:</p>

<p><i>&ldquo;The only way you can improve on things is to lock yourself up in a room and practice.&rdquo;</i></p>

<p>This might be a super asian way of thinking of things (I&rsquo;m asian) — <strong>BUT</strong> it has a lot of truths to it, especially if it’s a skill set in which individual work is important.</p>

<p>How does one become a great artist? A great engineer?</p>

<p><strong>Most likely through hours of practice alone.</strong></p>

<p>Whenever I’m trying to improve a skill, often times the best bet is to really immerse myself in the activity.</p>

<p>And <strong>to immerse myself in the activity, I can’t have other people around me, or have other distractions.</strong></p>

<h2>But it’s difficult when you have friends, social pressures, and obligations.</h2>

<p><strong>It’s also hard to say no.</strong></p>

<p>It was personally difficult for me to turn down invitations from my friends to go out and get drunk — <strong>but after my mathematician friend gave me his perspective, it made me feel fine about not always going out or being social.</strong></p>

<p>Social pressures can work for people or it can work against people. Since my friend encouraged me to feel okay about being a nerd, I&rsquo;ve encouraged my friends to do so as well.</p>

<p>This kind of creates an eco system where our group of friends can freely be nerds and be okay about it, and it works great.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re one of these people or want to make yourself feel better about being a nerd, please do message me and I will be super happy of making another hardworking nerdy friend.</p>
 ]]></content>
</entry>


  <entry>
  <title type="text">How to Learn How to Code while Getting Paid</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/How-To-Learn-How-to-Code-while-Getting-Paid.html" />
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/How-To-Learn-How-to-Code-while-Getting-Paid</id>
  <published>2016-03-20T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2016-03-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <h3>
  This was my stupid 3-step plan to becoming a superstar hacker 2 years ago when I first attempted to learn how to code:
</h3>




<ol>
  <li>Go through Codecademy courses</li>
  <li>Enroll in CS50</li>
  <li>Become a superstar coder</li>
</ol>




<p>
  I thought that this was all I needed to do in order for me to start creating the next Facebook.
</p>




<h1>WRONG.</h1>




<h3>
  This is what happened instead:
</h3>




<p>
  I blew through the Codecademy HTML/CSS and JavaScript/jQuery course and then quickly enrolled in CS50 (online introductory computer science course held by Harvard). Phew! After I finish CS50, I'll be amazing! - or so I thought.
</p>




<h3>Not Quite.</h3>




<p>
  For the first 3 lectures, I sat in my "virtual class environment" (my sofa + laptop) super excited about programming. And of course, as any one supposedly embarking on a new adventure would, I thought CS50 was going to change my life. The lecturer was super easy to understand, energetic, and to the point. They did a great job presenting the information and I thought I was learning a whole lot.
</p>




<p>
  But then after a couple of lectures, I was confused as <strong>#%!&</strong>. Pointers? Memory allocation? <strong>Programming suddenly seemed like a super complex thing to learn.</strong> The course went on about bubble sorts and merge sorts and all sorts of sorts. I was becoming more and more confused and I simply couldn't manage my motivation.
</p>




<h3>After 3 weeks, I had quit.</h3>




<p>
  My mind was spiraling with negative thoughts: <em>"I'm not smart enough for this. Coding is for smart people. Coding is for mathy people. I'm not fit for this."</em>
</p>




<p>
  Plus, even though I breezed through the Codecademy stuff, I had forgot most of the stuff that I had learned in a matter of a few weeks! <strong>This was a terrible, terrible investment of my time.</strong>
</p>




<hr>




<p>
  Then in August 2015, I had the urge to give coding a try once again and joined a coding bootcamp called <a href="http://www.thefirehoseproject.com" target="_blank">The Firehose Project</a>. It was the best decision I made that year. (I talk more about coding bootcamps in <a href="http://takehiromouri.com/Coding-Bootcamps-vs-Computer-Science.html" target="_blank">this post</a> and how it has changed my life in many ways in non-woowoo pseudo-science ways.)
</p>




<p>
  In short, the coding bootcamp was a super positive experience for me and lead me to land multiple jobs as a developer as well as dive deeper into programming and eventually computer science as well. The bootcamp's teaching methodologies enabled me to learn much quicker and much faster than going through Codecademy or CS50 or anything of that sort. 
</p>




<h3>
  I hear a lot of close friends wanting to learn how to learn how to code, so this is a post that will talk about what <strong><em>I think</em></strong> is the best and fastest way to start coding based on my <strong><em>personal experiences</em></strong>.
</h3>




<hr>




<h1>Step 1. Learn and Understand</h1>




<p>
  The first step is to <strong>learn and understand</strong>. Here's exactly how I go about it:
</p>




<ul>
  <li>Google "Best resources for learning <em>&lt;programming language/framework here&gt;</em>"</li>
  <li>If there is a Quora post, click on that (Quora tends to have higher quality answers)</li>
  <li>Surf around other search results and find the common resources that show up in multiple places</li>
  <li>Look through the common resources and see which ones excites me most</li>
  <li>Start learning with the resources</li>
</ul>




<p>
  The material you use for learning programming is super important. If you are spending 10 hours learning something, then the 10 hours better be spent learning material that is <strong>relevant and easy to understand</strong>. <strong>You don't want to spend hours and hours on resources that are hard to understand or not engaging - they are simply just a waste of time.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  You'll see sites like Codecademy come up in your Google search, and you might be wondering if it's actually a good resource since I mentioned how it <em>didn't</em> work for me earlier in this post.
</p>




<p>
  Despite my lack of success with Codecademy initially, I actually recommend it (and also websites similar to it) - it's great for learning the gist of the language. <strong>However, the important thing is to transition to Step 2 immediately after finishing this step. Otherwise, you'll just forget most of the stuff you learned (like I did initially).</strong>
</p>




<h1>Step 2. Build and Break</h1>




<p>
  You now understand the gist of the programming language or framework and how it works.
</p>




<p>
  The next step is to <strong>build and break</strong>. This means going out and actually <strong>building</strong> something with the stuff you just learned and then fixing bugs as they come along. Bugs are inevitable, but you can learn a lot from bugs and broken code. <strong>You want to start building with the assumption that you're going to be writing bad code - and then improving it.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  There are 2 steps to this, in my opinion. First, it's smart to go through some tutorials, or else you'll be completely lost. Once you've done some tutorials and feel comfortable, you should go and build your own project:
</p>




<!-- <h3>If it's your first time with the language or framework</h3>
<p>
  - go through some tutorials first
</p>

<h3>If you've already built something in Step 1</h3>
<p>
  - if you feel comfortable, then start building your own project.
</p>
<p>
  - if you don't feel comfortable yet, then start another tutorial until you really understand how most of the stuff works.
</p> -->




<h2>Step 2-a. Tutorials</h2>




<p>
  Again, finding good tutorials are key here. Many times, the reputable tutorials show up in the results in Step 1, when searching for resources on whatever you're trying to learn.
</p>




<p>
  If you've finished a tutorial or two and feel like you're ready to start building your app.
</p>




<h2>Step 2-b. Building Your Own Project</h2>




<p>
  In this step, you're going to be building your own project. Not following tutorials, not following directions. You're going to have to do everything yourself - but this is where you'll learn the most.
</p>




<h3>How to Pick a Project (this is the hardest part)</h3>




<p>
  In my experience, picking a project to work on is the most difficult part of this process. This is because if you pick a project that is a lousy idea, you just won't stick with it.
</p>




<p>
  For example, one time I tried building a diary app with Ruby on Rails for no reason. After building out some of the basic functionality, I realized that Google Drive does the job better and it gave me no reason to keep building the app - <strong>never try building something for no reason</strong>.
</p>




<h3>But coming up with a good project idea is hard...</h3>




<p>
  <strong>TRUE.</strong>
</p>




<h1>
  <strong>So here's my suggestion: Go out and sell your services.</strong>
</h1>




<h3><strong>Here's why:</strong></h3>


<p>
  <strong>If someone is paying you to build something, you're going to work your butt off to try and get everything right. You're going to be forced to learn at a super high speed in order to not mess anything up.</strong>
</p>




<h3><strong>BUT HOW?!</strong></h3>


<p>
  <strong>A lot of people want websites or web applications built for them, but lack the money to hire developers.</strong> They have ideas, but they lack the skills to actually build them. This is their thought process: 
</p>




<p>
  "I have an idea that will make millions and will be the next (Facebook, Uber, replace popular start up name here) - <strong><em>if only I had a coder to build my app</em></strong>."
</p>




<p>
  <strong>This is where you come in.</strong> Find these people and talk to them. Offer your services for super cheap at first and <strong>make an offer so sweet that they have no reason to reject you.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  This was how I pitched myself to 2 guys who wanted to build a company based on a web app: <strong><em>"Yes, I am indeed a noob, but if you hire non-noobs, it will cost you tens of thousands. If you hire me, I can build out this app and it won't cost you tens of thousands. Instead, it will only be hundreds or maybe a couple thousand at most. Plus, if you don't like the website, you can decide not to use it and pay me nothing."</em></strong>
</p>




<h3><strong>This is why this worked (at least for me):</strong></h3>




<p>
  <strong>What was the number one thing they wanted?</strong> <em>Their idea to be built out.</em>
</p>




<p>
  <strong>What was their number one constraint?</strong> <em>Money.</em>
</p>




<p>
  <strong>If I were to pitch them, what would be their number one concern?</strong> <em>That I wasn't skilled enough and would be a waste of money.</em>
</p>




<p>
  <strong>My pitch incorporated all of these factors so that they had no reason to reject my offer.</strong> If they didn't like the website, they could scrap it and pay <strong><em>nothing</em></strong>.
</p>




<p>
  To initially build a portfolio, I personally think that it's a smart idea to price low and over-deliver (unless you're already experienced). As a side note, I did this when I first started my translation business as well and it worked that time as well. I priced my services lower than my competitors and over-delivered and built social proof.
</p>




<h2>Ask Yourself: Why exactly would they buy from me rather than somebody else?</h2>


<p>
  Would it be my price, my skill set, my past experiences, or some other factor?
</p>




<p>
  Since I had minimal skill to do the job, had no past experience, the only way I could differentiate was to set a lower price and work my butt off. And for a lot of people reading this article, I'm assuming this is probably the case.
</p>




<p><strong>So find somebody to build a website for, give a pitch that they can't turn down, and start working on the project.</strong> Once you pass this step, it's time to do anything you can do to finish the app and build something that would satisfy your clients.</p>




<p>
  This means Googling for solutions to any bugs/problems you might encounter, asking people questions, and finding solutions.
</p>




<h3>And <strong>this</strong> is where you'll be learning <strong>2x, 3x</strong> as fast as you would compared to going through more tutorials. <strong>You're forced to build out real-world ideas and forced to solve real-world problems.</strong></h3>




<h1>Examples</h1>




<p>
  I've given this advice to some people that were just starting out with their coding journey and it seems to have worked for them. One of my friends from <a href="http://www.thefirehoseproject.com" target="_blank">The Firehose Project</a>, Dany, asked for my advice. I told him mostly the same things that I laid out in this blog post and this was his response.
</p>


<p><img src="static/img/dany.png" alt="learning coding"></p>

<p>
  When I talked to him a couple of months after that, he told me that he took some of my advice and things were going quite well for him:
</p>


<p><img src="static/img/dany_2.png" alt="learning coding"></p>

<p>
  I've given the same advice to other people with the same results. It seems that it just makes sense - <strong>when you are forced to learn at an accelerated pace, you'll learn more quicker as a result.</strong>
</p>




<hr>




<p>
  Hopefully this blog post was somewhat helpful in motivating you to go out and grab a project that you can start working on (while maybe getting paid) to accelerate your learning speeds. This is something that's worked for me and the people around me, and I hope it works for the people reading this as well!
</p>



 ]]></content>
</entry>


  <entry>
  <title type="text">Using Spaced Repetition Software to Learn Programming Concepts</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/Using-Spaced-Repetition-Software-To-Learn-Programming-Concepts.html" />
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/Using-Spaced-Repetition-Software-To-Learn-Programming-Concepts</id>
  <published>2016-03-15T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2016-03-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>
  As a programmer who still has so much to learn, I strongly feel that finding the right tools and methodologies in learning how to program is super important. Learning is a hard skill - especially when it comes to increasing your knowledge around textbook type subjects. Reading a textbook and going through lectures are not always the most entertaining, and it can easily lead to a unproductive study session.
</p>




<p>
  I was studying for one of my computer science classes when I stumbled across <a href="https://sivers.org/srs" target="_blank">this post</a> by Derek Sivers. He explains it perfectly, so there's really no point of me explaining it:
</p>




<p><em>
  "When you hear a new fact, it's forgotten pretty quickly unless it's brought back to the forefront of your mind repeatedly. You can do this haphazardly by immersing yourself in a language, for example, where the new words you learn will be brought up by chance occasionally. <strong>But memory research shows that the most effective and efficient time for a new fact to be remembered is right before you were about to forget it.</strong> Say if you learn a new word in a foreign language, you'd want to practice it again a few minutes after hearing it, then a few hours, then the next day, then in 2 days, then 5 days, then 10 days, 3 weeks, 6 weeks, 3 months, 8 months, etc. After a while it's basically permanently memorized with a rare reminder. <strong>Spaced Repetition Software does this for you, so you can just give it a bunch of facts you want to remember, then have it quiz you once a day, and it manages the intervals based on your feedback. After each quiz question, if you say that one was easy, it won't be introduced for a long time, but if you were stumped, then it'll ask it again in a few minutes, until you've got it.</strong>" - Derek Sivers
</em></p>




<p>
  Basically Spaced Repetition Software, or SRS, is a flash card software that is optimized to increase your chances of learning based on memory research. Pretty cool stuff - but like a lot of you (I'm assuming), <strong>I was kind of skeptical that this would actually work.</strong>
</p>




<h1>These were my questions:</h1>


<ol>
  <li>Is this applicable to programming? - is it better to simply just Google stuff and code?</li>
  <li>Would I stick with it?</li>
</ol>




<h1>And here are my answers:</h1>




<p>
  After actually trying Anki (a popular SRS) out for 3 weeks now, here are my thoughts:
</p>




<h3>Is this applicable to programming? - is it better to simply just Google stuff and code?</h3>


<p>
  <strong>Yes - and no.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  What I've found that for a lot of things, it's just faster for Google to memorize. For example, if I were to use SRS to try and memorize how to reverse a string in Ruby, I could make a flashcard to remind myself every now and then. On the other hand, it takes 2 seconds to find out how to reverse a string in Ruby, so it really doesn't make sense to memorize it. If Googling will take less time, you shouldn't be trying to memorize it.
</p>




<p>
  On the flip side, <strong>SRS is great for learning programming concepts</strong>. A lot of times (atleast for me), I read about a concept and understand it (at the time) and then gain the feeling of satisfaction. But then in a few days when a friend asks me about the concept, my memory is fuzzy or I just don't remember (even though I read about it and understood it a few days back). Once I started using SRS to recall my understanding, it got easier for me to not only recall the concept, but actaully apply it in practice.
</p>




<p>
  This is more of a topic of learning methodology than it is of SRS - <strong>you need to find ways to recall information in order to retain your knowledge.</strong> That's why many people are avid note takers. SRS is just another way of retaining information - except it's super efficient.
</p>




<h1>Would I stick with it?</h1>




<p>
  <strong>Yes.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  The great thing about Anki is that it becomes addictive - every day you start up Anki, and it provides you with flashcards to go over for the day. Once you go through the flashcards, it feels like you've learned so much in a matter of 10 or 15 minutes.
</p>




<p>
  The difference between Anki and regular Flash Card applications is that Anki removes all the unnecessary going-through of flash cards for you - <strong>if you felt the question was easy yesterday, it won't tell you to answer the flash card the next day.</strong> That means less flash cards and better learning.
</p>




<p>
  Doing Anki every day has been so easy for me, just because of the way it's designed. It was easy for me to start a habit of using Anki and there are tons of people that would say the same thing as well.
</p>




<hr>




<p>
  If you're currently trying to learn difficult programming concepts, then SRS might be the way to go. AnkiSrs is free open source software that you can download <a href="http://ankisrs.net/" target="_blank">here</a>.
</p>




<p>
  I would highly recommend reading Derek Siver's post on SRS <a href="https://sivers.org/srs" target="_blank">here</a>, as it goes through the entire learning methodology involved in using SRS.
</p>



 ]]></content>
</entry>


  <entry>
  <title type="text">Coding Bootcamps vs Computer Science</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/Coding-Bootcamps-vs-Computer-Science.html" />
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/Coding-Bootcamps-vs-Computer-Science</id>
  <published>2016-03-03T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2016-03-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <h1>Coding Bootcamps vs Computer Science</h1>




<p>
  Joining a coding bootcamp was the best choice I made in my college career — and it could be the best choice you make as well, especially if you have never coded before. Coding bootcamps are a fairly new thing — <strong>they are intensive training schools where students can learn programming to a professional level in an extremely short period of time (12 ~ 15 weeks). By omitting computer science topics that aren’t really used in actual work and focusing solely on the practical skills that are used most in the industry, bootcamps are able to teach programming in an extremely short period of time.</strong> These coding bootcamps are mostly targeted towards adults who are looking for a career change or want to start their own businesses.
</p>




<p>
  I was an outlier, joining an online coding bootcamp called <a href="http://www.thefirehoseproject.com" target="_blank"><a href="http://www.thefirehoseproject.com" target="_blank">theFirehoseProject</a></a> as a college junior. Despite the fact that coding bootcamps usually aren’t targeted towards college undergraduates like me, I’ve found that going through the bootcamp as an undergrad has been one of the most rewarding experiences in my college life. <strong>Here’s why:</strong>
</p>




<h1>Coding Bootcamps vs Computer Science</h1>




<p>
   <strong>How are coding bootcamps different from traditional Computer Science courses?</strong> This is a question that gets asked a lot, and is a question that I was asking before I joined. Here are my impressions based on my own experiences of experiencing both.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>Coding bootcamps focus greatly on applicable skills and modern technologies being used by the industry.</strong> Many focus on teaching Ruby, a modern programming language, which is also a great first language since it is a “programmer friendly” language and is relatively easier to grasp compared to a language like C or Java.
</p>




<p>
  On the other hand, <strong>many computer science classes start with relatively difficult languages like C or Java.</strong> These languages might be essential to learn as a coder, but they tend to be the difficult for beginners to grasp, and <strong>many people quit coding at this point. I was one of these people, when I tried learning programming with CS50, a famous online course offered by Harvard.</strong> The course itself was fantastic and high quality, but the programming language I was taught was C. Although this might be pedagogically better as it forces you to learn the intricacies of programming, it might also scare beginners away, <strong>giving the false impression that learning a programming language is difficult to learn, when in fact, it isn’t.</strong>
</p>


<p><figure>
  <img src="static/img/mathishard.jpg" alt="Coding Bootcamps vs Computer Science" />
  <figcaption>Mathematics and computer science go hand in hand — but you don’t need so much math for most types of programming you’ll actually do in your job</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>
  <strong>Another point to make is that a lot of intermediate to advanced computer science courses require some mathematics and thus have a higher barrier to entry.</strong> Mathematical thinking is important, but is only required in a limited variety of programming jobs. Coding bootcamps do a great job of taking out a lot of the unnecessary math for developing web applications in their curriculum, thus creating a low barrier to entry.
</p>




<p>
  Since the objective of bootcamps are to train total newbie programmers into professionals in a short period of time, the top bootcamps do a great job in teaching things in a way that a complete beginner can understand. The curriculum and lesson style at <a href="http://www.thefirehoseproject.com" target="_blank">theFirehoseProject</a> was indeed, extremely easy to understand as a beginner. After 7 weeks upon training with <a href="http://www.thefirehoseproject.com" target="_blank">theFirehoseProject</a>, I was able to land a job as a web developer at a local start up. With that, I was able to pay off most of my bootcamp tuition fees, so already it was a great investment.
</p>


<p><img src="static/img/csinfographic.jpg" alt="Coding Bootcamps vs Computer Science"></p>

<h1>How new opportunities opened up as I learned to code</h1>




<p><strong>Being able to code opened up a tremendous amount of opportunities on and off campus.</strong></p>




<p>
  In my 8th week, I participated in a student hackathon called HackNC (hackathons are typically events where teams try to hack together something cool within a 24 ~ 48 hour timeframe). I worked with a team of 2 other developers and 1 business student, and we were able to hack together a minimally viable product after working 24 hours straight. I was in charge of doing a lot of the front end work which I was already used to doing from the curriculum at <a href="http://www.thefirehoseproject.com" target="_blank">theFirehoseProject</a>. We ended up receiving 3 prizes at the hackathon along with offers from multiple companies in my first hackathon. The team that I worked with at that event are still buddies and it was overall a great experience that was made possible because I joined a coding bootcamp.
</p>


<p><figure>
  <img src="static/img/guru.png" alt="Coding Bootcamps vs Computer Science">
  <img src="static/img/guru_2.png" alt="Coding Bootcamps vs Computer Science">
  <figcaption>Front end stuff I hacked together at the hackathon after 9 weeks of training at <a href="http://www.thefirehoseproject.com" target="_blank">theFirehoseProject</a></figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>
  <strong>Outside of school, being able to code also led me to gaining some work experience.</strong> I saw a Facebook post by a person who wanted to build a web application for their new business idea. Plus, they were willing to pay for it. I was only in my 7th week, but figured I’d at least give it a try. Since I had already built a couple of web applications, I told them that despite being relatively a beginner at coding, I knew how to build basic web applications and could work with them to build out their idea for cheaper. They also liked the idea of giving a college kid some experience, as well as the costs that they were able to cut, and so they hired me (that gig alone paid for my tuition at the bootcamp).
</p>




<h1>If you’re in college why didn’t you just take computer science courses?</h1>




<p>
  Well you might be thinking by now, <i><strong>if you’re in college and wanted to learn how to code, why didn’t you just take Computer Science courses in the first place?</strong></i>
</p>




<p><strong>The answer to this question is simple: I thought I wasn’t smart enough to learn how to code.</strong></p>




<p>
  <strong>The common misconception is that coding is a super difficult skill to learn. It’s not.</strong> You just have to have the right support system, motivation, and resources to overcome the initial barriers that you might face when starting out. I learned that through joining a bootcamp.
</p>


<p><figure>
<img src="static/img/banghead.jpg" alt="Coding Bootcamps vs Computer Science" style="width:200px;margin: 0 auto;display:block">
<figcaption>Me when I first tried to learn how to code through a computer science course</figcaption>
</figure></p>

<p>
  If I hadn’t joined a bootcamp, I wouldn’t have decided to not only take computer science courses, but also major in it as well. Although being able to code was a dream for me, I tried and I failed with my initial dab at it with CS50, the Harvard CS course I mentioned before. The course taught in C and immediately went into sorting algorithms. This gave me the initial impression that learning to program was hard.
</p>




<p>
  <strong>But the truth is, learning how to program isn’t as hard as you might think. You just need to start with a programmer friendly language with an awesome support system and friendly community. That’s what bootcamps are able to provide.</strong>
</p>




<p>
  So if you’re a college student and you’ve been wanting to learn programming but just thought it wasn’t for you, <strong>take a look at some top coding bootcamps</strong> (some bootcamps are apparently not worth the money so make sure to look at the top schools). You might be surprised to find that <strong>anyone can learn how to code given the right resources. Once you start learning how to code, you’ll see new opportunities open up to you that you’ve never realized before.</strong>
</p>




<h3>
  I don’t think that coding bootcamps can replace computer science courses at this point in time— they are just two different things. Computer science is a study of computers and not just simply programming. On the other hand, coding bootcamps equip you with practical skills to build basic web applications and join a team as a junior developer.
</h3>


<p></p>

<p>
  So if you’re interested in learning how to code but don’t want to get into the computer science topics, then joining a bootcamp might be the right choice for you.
</p>




<h3>
  Here’s a list of bootcamps that I’ve heard great things about that you can take a look at: 
</h3>




<p>
  <a href="http://www.thefirehoseproject.com/" target="_blank"><a href="http://www.thefirehoseproject.com" target="_blank">The Firehose Project</a></a> — A extremely reasonably priced online Ruby on Rails coding bootcamp ($4,000) with a super helpful team and supporting community. With weekly mentor sessions with top notch developers, you can really grow at a fast pace as a developer. The curriculum is intensive, where you get the best of both worlds with a combination of practical web development skills with computer science topics such as Data Structures and Algorithms. It’s also perfect for people that don’t want to quit their jobs and spend a ton of money. I personally recommend it for most people because of it's learn by doing approach and algorithm training that is necessary to succeed in technical job interviews. The student community is very active and there are always interactions going on in the private Slack channel. The mentors are top notch developers, the curriculum is top notch, and overall I highly recommend the Firehose Project.
</p>




<p>
  <a href="http://www.hackreactor.com/" target="_blank">HackReactor</a> — This bootcamp costs $18,000 to enroll, but it’s supposed to be well worth the money. If you are looking to go to a top notch bootcamp and are willing to pay the money, HackReactor is probably the bootcamp for you.
</p>




<p>
  <a href="http://www.fullstackacademy.com/" target="_blank">Fullstack Academy</a> — Also another immersive bootcamp like HackReactor. Their student projects are super impressive, which is always a great sign.
</p>




<p>
  <a href="http://www.makersquare.com/" target="_blank">Makersquare</a> — Similar to HackReactor and Fullstack Academy. Full time coding bootcamps with a focus on JavaScript frameworks. They claim to have high rates of graduates getting jobs.
</p>



 ]]></content>
</entry>


  <entry>
  <title type="text">Caching in Rails - How ETags and fresh_when work</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/Rails-Caching-How-ETags-and-fresh_when-work.html" />
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/Rails-Caching-How-ETags-and-fresh_when-work</id>
  <published>2016-02-25T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2016-02-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>
  To make web pages load faster, caching is super important. Let's first look at what caching means:
</p>




<p>
  <q><i>Caching means to store content generated during the request-response cycle and to reuse it when responding to similar requests</i></q> (from <a href="http://edgeguides.rubyonrails.org/caching_with_rails.html" target="_blank">Rails Guides</a>)
</p>




<p>
  Let's break down what happens when a request is sent to a server to figure out what this all means:
</p>




<h4>First Request</h4>


<ol>
  <li>A request is sent to server</li>
  <li>Renders entire response body</li>
  <li>Generates an ETag by doing an MD% hash on entire response body (looks like below)</li>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">headers</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;ETag&#39;</span><span class="o">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">Digest</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">MD5</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">hexdigest</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">body</span><span class="p">)</span></code></pre></figure>

  <li>
    Rails sends back the response body as well as the ETag as a header field to the client (usually a browser)
  </li>
  <li>The client caches the response and stores the ETag</li>
</ol>




<h4>Second Request</h4>


<ol>
  <li>We request the same page again</li>
  <li>The client sends the stored ETag as a <code>If-None-Match</code>header</li>
  <li>Renders entire reponse body</li>
  <li>Generates an ETag in the same way as previous</li>
  <li>Compares ETag that was sent as header to the one that was just generated</li>
  <li>If it matched, then the body is not sent to the client and instead sent a <code>304</code> not modified status</li>
</ol>




<p>
  Basically if the page isn't modified, the browser reads the page from the cache.
</p>




<h3>So what are ETags?</h3>


<p>
  <strong>ETags</strong> stands for <strong>Entity Tags</strong>. It's essentially a key to see if the page has changed or not.
</p>




<p>
  From a client side perspective, this is awesome because now we don't have to re-download everything, everything is stored in the cache.
</p>




<p>
  But from a server side perspective, it still has to generate the ETag every single time there is a request. Processing the entire response body everytime we want to generate an ETag is not the most efficient.
</p>




<h3>Introducing <code>fresh_when</code></h3>


<p>
  You can set your custom ETags with <code>fresh_when</code>. For example, let's say you have a blog application and you want to tell rails to update the cache when an article has been updated or created. You can simply add <code>fresh_when</code> in your controller action. In this case, we're going to add it in the <code>show</code> action.
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">show</span>
  <span class="vi">@article</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">Article</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">find</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">params</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="ss">:id</span><span class="o">]</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="n">fresh_when</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="vi">@article</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  What this does is generate an ETag for us like this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">headers</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;Etag&#39;</span><span class="o">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">Digest</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">MD5</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">hexdigest</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="vi">@article</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">cache_key</span><span class="p">)</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  The <code>cache_key</code> is what keeps track of if something has updated. For instance, <code>@article.cache_key</code> would look something like <code>'article/23-2016-224150000'</code>.
</p>




<p>
  The <code>cache_key</code> is generated in this format: <code>&lt;model name&gt;/&lt;id&gt;-&lt;updated_at&gt;</code>.
</p>




<hr>




<p>
  According to <a href="https://robots.thoughtbot.com/introduction-to-conditional-http-caching-with-rails" target="_blank">a simple test that thoughtbot ran</a>, performance improved by 94% (33ms to 2ms) just by including one <code>fresh_when</code> in a controller action. That's an amazing improvement.
</p>




<p>
  As we can see <code>fresh_when</code> is a powerful tool that we can use to improve our caching. Instead of processing the whole response body, we can focus on tracking if a resource is stale or fresh by using <code>fresh_when</code>.
</p>




<p>
  Happy coding!
</p>



 ]]></content>
</entry>


  <entry>
  <title type="text">How to Write Better Ruby Methods - The Composed Method Technique</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/How-to-write-better-ruby-methods-The-Composed-Method-Technique.html" />
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/How-to-write-better-ruby-methods-The-Composed-Method-Technique</id>
  <published>2016-02-24T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2016-02-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>
  In my search to write better code, I've stumbled across a technique to write better methods. It's called <strong>The Composed Method Technique</strong> (from <a href="https://read.amazon.com/kp/embed?asin=B004MMEJ36&preview=newtab&linkCode=kpe&ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_JqsYwb0AAT5XE" target="_blank">Eloquent Ruby</a>).
</p>




<p>
  The composed method technique basically has 3 rules.
</p>


<p><strong>
  <ol>
    <li>Each method should do a single thing</li>
    <li>Each method needs to operate at a single conceptual level</li>
    <li>Each method needs to have a name that reflects its purpose</li>
  </ol>
</strong></p>

<p>
  Let's walk through what each of these rules mean.
</p>




<h3>Each method should do a single thing</h3>


<p>
  Each method should focus on solving a single aspect of the problem. So if your method is solving two problems, then you should be creating a new method. For example, consider the following method that determines if one should transition from one relationship to another:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">transition</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">numeric_love_level</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">current_partner</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">7</span>
  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">life_partner_material?</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">current_partner</span><span class="p">)</span>
    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">side_chick</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">exists?</span> <span class="o">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class="n">current_partner</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">knows_about_side_chick?</span> <span class="o">||</span> <span class="nb">self</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">cant_take_anymore_crap</span>
      <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Sorry, we can&#39;t be together anymore&quot;</span>
      <span class="n">current_partner</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">null</span>
      <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">side_chick</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">exists?</span>
        <span class="n">side_chick</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">send_message</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;Wanna netflix and chill?&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
      <span class="k">else</span>
        <span class="n">tinder</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">find_partner</span>
      <span class="k">end</span>
    <span class="k">end</span>
  <span class="k">end</span>
<span class="k">end</span></p>

<p><span class="c1"># other methods of figuring out relationship problems</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  This is such messy code (and a horrible algorithm to begin with...) The <code>transition</code> method does so many things: it tries to see if there's still love between the two, it tries to see if the partner is life partner material, it tries to see if a side chick exists and if the partner knows about her, and if so, break up with the partner and seek out other potentials. All in all, this method is a <i>mess</i>. Again, <strong>each method should do a single thing</strong>.
</p>




<p>
  Let's seperate each problem into a method and see what it looks like (still a horrible algorithm):
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">transition</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">love_still_exists?</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="kp">false</span> <span class="k">unless</span> <span class="n">break_up?</span>
  <span class="n">break_up!</span>
  <span class="n">find_new_partner</span>
<span class="k">end</span></p>

<p><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">love_still_exists?</span>
  <span class="n">numeric_love_level</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">current_partner</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">7</span> <span class="o">?</span> <span class="kp">false</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="kp">true</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="kp">true</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">life_partner_material?</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">current_partner</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="c1"># other complicated relationship stuff below</span>
<span class="k">end</span></p>

<p><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">break_up?</span>
  <span class="n">side_chick</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">exists?</span> <span class="o">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class="n">current_partner</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">knows_about_side_chick?</span> <span class="p">?</span> <span class="kp">true</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="kp">false</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="kp">true</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="nb">self</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">cant_take_anymore_crap</span>
  <span class="kp">false</span>
  <span class="c1"># what a crappy algorithm to figure out if you should break up or not :/</span>
<span class="k">end</span></p>

<p><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">break_up!</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Sorry, we can&#39;t be together anymore&quot;</span>
  <span class="n">current_partner</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">null</span>
<span class="k">end</span></p>

<p><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">find_new_partner</span>
  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">side_chick</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">exists?</span>
    <span class="n">side_chick</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">send_message</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;Wanna netflix and chill?&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="k">else</span>
    <span class="n">tinder</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">find_partner</span>
  <span class="k">end</span>
<span class="k">end</span></p>

<p><span class="c1"># other methods of figuring out relationship problems</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  Although I advise absolutely no one to try out this algorithm in real life, the code itself is much easier to read and understand. Splitting the methods into small little chunks result in better code.
</p>




<h3>Each method nees to operate at a single conceptual level</h3>


<p>
  This basically means not to mix high-level logic with the nitty-gritty details. For example, the <code>transition</code> method holds high-level logic and branches out to other methods:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">transition</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">love_still_exists?</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="kp">false</span> <span class="k">unless</span> <span class="n">break_up?</span>
  <span class="n">break_up!</span>
  <span class="n">find_new_partner</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  What we don't want is something like this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">transition</span>
  <span class="c1"># high-level logic</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">love_still_exists?</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="kp">false</span> <span class="k">unless</span> <span class="n">break_up?</span>
  <span class="c1"># nitty gritty details here</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Sorry, we can&#39;t be together anymore&quot;</span>
  <span class="n">current_partner</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">null</span>
  <span class="c1"># nitty gritty details again</span>
  <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">side_chick</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">exists?</span>
    <span class="n">side_chick</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">send_message</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;Wanna netflix and chill?&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="k">else</span>
    <span class="n">tinder</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">find_partner</span>
  <span class="k">end</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  It's much better organized if the conceptual level is constant as we saw in the above example.
</p>




<h3>Each method needs to have a name that reflects its purpose</h3>


<p>
  This one is quite straightforward. In essense, what we don't want is something like this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">eat_cheeseburger</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Sorry, we can&#39;t be together anymore&quot;</span>
  <span class="n">current_partner</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">null</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  or this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">draw_circle</span>
  <span class="n">numeric_love_level</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">current_partner</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="mi">7</span> <span class="o">?</span> <span class="kp">false</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="kp">true</span>
  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="kp">true</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">life_partner_material?</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">current_partner</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="c1"># other complicated relationship stuff below</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  A method named <code>eat_cheeseburger</code> is expected to eat a cheese burger, not say a cliche break up quote and set <code>current_partner</code> to <code>null</code>. Similarly, a method named <code>draw_circle</code> is expected to draw a circle, not figure out complicated love matters.
</p>




<p>
  In this situation, <code>break_up!</code> or <code>love_still_exists?</code> makes 500% more sense.
</p>




<h3>Writing Shorter Methods</h3>


<p>
  Applying the composed method technique allows you to write shorter and smaller methods instead of long ones. There are several merits to writing shorter methods in Ruby.
</p>




<p>
  The first is that <strong>writing smaller details will help you get the details correct</strong>. It's the same idea to writing pseudocode - except you are defining a new method for each line of pseudocode.
</p>




<p>
  The second is that <strong>it's easier to test with smaller methods</strong>. If a method contains a solution to more than one problem, you can't isolate a buggy solution; you can only test the entire method. If you have methods that are divided into seperate purposes, you can isolate them and test if they work. It's much easier to debug this way.
</p>




<p>
  The last upside is that in Ruby, the composed method way of defining and building classes is super effective since <strong>the cost of defining a new method in Ruby is extremely low</strong>. You just need an additional <code>def</code> and <code>end</code>. In other languages, it can take a little bit more code and thus a little bit more costly. The cost performance of defining a new method in Ruby is high and there's really no reason not to define a new method.
</p>




<p>
  <strong><i>Unless</i></strong> you are over doing the "short methods" thing. Your "short method" should actually do something and you shouldn't just define a short method because you can:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">break_up!</span>
  <span class="n">say_cliche_break_up_line</span>
  <span class="n">set_current_partner_to_null</span>
<span class="k">end</span></p>

<p><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">say_cliche_break_up_line</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Sorry, we can&#39;t be together anymore&quot;</span>
<span class="k">end</span></p>

<p><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">set_current_partner_to_null</span>
  <span class="n">current_partner</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">null</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="c1"># this is over doing it</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<hr>




<p>
  I hope my poorly thoughout algorithm was able to explain the topic of writing better methods in Ruby. I apologize for my lack of relationship intelligence, if you have any suggestions please reach out to me as I would like to refactor my poorly constructed model of how one should transition between relationships.
</p>




<p>
  Happy coding!
</p>



 ]]></content>
</entry>


  <entry>
  <title type="text">Useful techniques for arrays and strings in ruby</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/Useful-techniques-for-arrays-and-strings-in-ruby.html" />
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/Useful-techniques-for-arrays-and-strings-in-ruby</id>
  <published>2016-02-22T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2016-02-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>
  Ruby comes with several useful techniques that you can use to manipulate various data types. In this post, I'll go over some particularly useful techniques that can be used with arrays and strings in Ruby.
</p>




<h3>Using <code>%w{ }</code> to declare an array of strings</h3>




<p>
  You can declare an array of strings like this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">array</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="s1">&#39;I&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;am&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;a&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;little&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s1">&#39;pony&#39;</span><span class="o">]</span>
<span class="c1"># [&quot;I&quot;, &quot;am&quot;, &quot;a&quot;, &quot;little&quot;, &quot;pony&quot;]</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  There's another way you can declare strings that don't contain strings, which you may find a to be pretty convenient:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">array</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="sx">%w{I am a little pony}</span>
<span class="c1"># [&quot;I&quot;, &quot;am&quot;, &quot;a&quot;, &quot;little&quot;, &quot;pony&quot;]</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  It takes less time to type but results in the same thing.
</p>




<h3>Using <code>find_index</code></h3>




<p>
  To find the index of an object in array, the <code>find_index</code> method comes in handy:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">words</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="sx">%w{I am a little pony}</span>
<span class="n">words</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">find_index</span><span class="p">{</span><span class="o">|</span><span class="n">word</span><span class="o">|</span> <span class="n">word</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s2">&quot;pony&quot;</span><span class="p">}</span>
<span class="c1"># returns 4</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<h3>The Inject Method</h3>




<p>
  When you want to get the sum of all numbers in an array, the <code>inject</code> method allows you to do so in an elegant way:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">numbers</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">4</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">5</span><span class="o">]</span>
<span class="n">numbers</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">inject</span><span class="p">{</span><span class="o">|</span><span class="n">sum</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">num</span><span class="o">|</span> <span class="n">sum</span> <span class="o">+=</span> <span class="n">num</span><span class="p">}</span>
<span class="c1"># returns 15</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  <code>inject</code> is like an <code>each</code> loop, in that it iterates through each element of the array and performs something with each element. <code>inject</code> takes in 2 arguments. The first argument (<code>sum</code>) is the result of the expression performed in the block. In this case, it is the result of <code>sum += num</code>. The second argument (<code>num</code>) is the element in the array in which the iteration is currently on. For example, the first time around, <code>num</code> will equal <code>1</code>, the second time around, <code>num</code> will equal <code>2</code>.
</p>




<p>
  <code>sum</code> by default is initialized at <code>0</code>, but you can specify another value like such:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">numbers</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">4</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">5</span><span class="o">]</span>
<span class="n">numbers</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">inject</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">100</span><span class="p">){</span><span class="o">|</span><span class="n">sum</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">num</span><span class="o">|</span> <span class="n">sum</span> <span class="o">+=</span> <span class="n">num</span><span class="p">}</span>
<span class="c1"># returns 115</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  in which case it returns <code>115</code>.
</p>




<h3>No more escapes with <code>%q{ }</code></h3>




<p>
  Isn't it annoying when you have to do something like this?
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">string_full_of_escapes</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s1">&#39;I&amp;#39;m in love with Ruby. &quot;Ruby isn&amp;#39;t just a language, it&amp;#39;s a lifestyle&quot;. &#39;</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  Instead, you could simple do this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">no_escape_string</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="sx">%q{I&#39;m in love with Ruby. &quot;Ruby isn&#39;t just a language, it&#39;s a lifestyle.&quot;}</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  The <code>q</code> stands for quotes, and it invokes single quotes for you. Beware that <code>#{}</code> won't work with single quotes, and only works with double quotes. In that case, you want to use <code>Q%{ }</code> instead:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="nb">name</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Takehiro&quot;</span>
<span class="sx">%Q{My name is </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="sx">}</span>
<span class="c1"># &quot;My name is Takehiro&quot;</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<hr>




<p>
  Happy coding!
</p>



 ]]></content>
</entry>


  <entry>
  <title type="text">Using case statements to declare variables</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/Using-case-statements-to-declare-variables.html" />
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/Using-case-statements-to-declare-variables</id>
  <published>2016-02-21T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2016-02-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>
  If you wanted to assign different variables depending on several different situations, you might be tempted to do so like this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">model</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Apple MacBook Air 13.3&#39;</span>
  <span class="n">price</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">999</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mo">00</span>
<span class="k">elsif</span> <span class="n">model</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Apple MacBook Pro with Retina Display 13.3&#39;</span>
  <span class="n">price</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">1169</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mo">00</span>
<span class="k">elsif</span> <span class="n">model</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Apple MacBook Pro with Retina Display 15&#39;</span>
  <span class="n">price</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mi">1849</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mo">00</span>
<span class="k">else</span>
  <span class="n">price</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Could not find model&quot;</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  In these situations, ruby offers a more elegant solution using <strong>case statements</strong> to do the same thing. It turns out that you can use case statements to declare variables like this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">price</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="k">case</span> <span class="n">model</span>
        <span class="k">when</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Apple MacBook Air 13.3&#39;</span> <span class="k">then</span> <span class="mi">999</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mo">00</span>
        <span class="k">when</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Apple MacBook Pro with Retina Display 13.3&#39;</span> <span class="k">then</span> <span class="mi">1169</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mo">00</span>
        <span class="k">when</span> <span class="s1">&#39;Apple MacBook Pro with Retina Display 15&#39;</span> <span class="k">then</span> <span class="mi">1849</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="mo">00</span>
        <span class="k">else</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Could not find model&quot;</span>
        <span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  This is a quick little trick that you could use in this common situation.
</p>




<p>
  Happy coding! :)
</p>

 ]]></content>
</entry>


  <entry>
  <title type="text">5 Tips for Beginners to Write Better Ruby Code Instantly</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.takehiromouri.com/5-tips-for-beginners-to-write-better-ruby-code-instantly.html" />
  <id>https://www.takehiromouri.com/5-tips-for-beginners-to-write-better-ruby-code-instantly</id>
  <published>2016-02-20T00:00:00Z</published>
  <updated>2016-02-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <content type="html"><![CDATA[ <p>
  Now that you've learned the basic syntax and gained a basic understanding of ruby works, you want to learn how to write better and more concise code. Here are 5 quick tips picked up from a fantastic book called <a href="https://read.amazon.com/kp/embed?asin=B004MMEJ36&preview=newtab&linkCode=kpe&ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_JqsYwb0AAT5XE" target="_blank">Eloquent Ruby</a> that you can start using right now to make your code more readable.
</p>




<h2>Don't write comments for the wrong reasons</h2>




<p>
  Adding comments, especially in a more complex app can be useful. You have to make sure that you provide comments so that other people can read and understand your code. You also have to make sure that you can understand the code yourself after a while.
</p>




<p>
  On the other hand, you don't want to get in the mindset of, <i>"Oh, this code is pretty messy but I'm going to add comments so it'll be fine."</i> Adding comments to make badly written code somewhat comprehensible is an extremely bad reason for adding comments. <strong>In general, your ruby code should be clear enough so that it explains itself.</strong> Hence the quote from the book, <strong><i>"Good code is like a good joke: it needs no explanation."</i></strong> <span style="font-size:12px;">(pg. 8 - Eloquent Ruby)</span>
</p>




<h2>Ternary Operators</h2>


<p>
  Ever write code like this?
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">subscribed?</span>
  <span class="n">render_already_subscribed_message</span>
<span class="k">else</span>
  <span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">subscribe!</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  This makes perfect sense, except we can make it much shorter with ternary operators. Ternary operators work like such:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">if_this_is_a_true_value</span> <span class="p">?</span> <span class="n">then_the_result_is_this</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">else_it_is_this</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
   So in this example, we can re-write the code like this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">subscribed?</span> <span class="p">?</span> <span class="n">render_already_subscribed_message</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">subscribe!</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<h2>Method Name Conventions: Using <code>?</code> and <code>!</code></h2>


<p>
  When you are using ruby, you may have noticed that a lot of the built in methods use <code>?</code> and <code>!</code>. For example <code>.nil?</code> or <code>.flatten!</code>. <code>?</code> and <code>!</code> aren't special symbols in method names, but rather just naming conventions in the ruby community.
</p>




<p>
  <code>?</code>s are used when the method returns a <code>true</code> or <code>false</code> boolean. So for example instead of this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">is_legal</span>
  <span class="nb">self</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">age</span> <span class="o">&gt;=</span> <span class="mi">21</span>
<span class="k">end</span></p>

<p><span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">is_legal</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  You want to write add a <code>?</code> to the method like this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">is_legal?</span>
  <span class="nb">self</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">age</span> <span class="o">&gt;=</span> <span class="mi">21</span>
<span class="k">end</span></p>

<p><span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">is_legal?</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  You can see here that <code>current_user.is_legal?</code> makes a little more sense than <code>current_user.is_legal</code>, since we are essentially asking a yes or no question.
</p>




<p>
  Now let's take a look at the <code>!</code> operator in methods. The <code>!</code> operator when used in a method infers that the method is potentially dangerous and could change the state of the variable that the method is called upon. Here's an example:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">a</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">4</span><span class="o">]</span></p>

<p><span class="nb">print</span> <span class="n">a</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">reverse</span></p>

<p><span class="nb">print</span> <span class="n">a</span>
<span class="c1"># returns [1, 2, 3, 4]</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  What we see here is that we expect <code>.reverse</code> to actually modify the array <code>a</code>. However, we see that it doesn't modify the actual array, but it just returns the reversed array. Now what if we change the <code>reverse</code> method to <code>reverse!</code>?
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="n">a</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="o">[</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="mi">4</span><span class="o">]</span></p>

<p><span class="nb">print</span> <span class="n">a</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">reverse!</span></p>

<p><span class="nb">print</span> <span class="n">a</span>
<span class="c1"># returns [4, 3, 2, 1]</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  Now we see that <code>reverse!</code> has actually modified the actual array. It's important to know the differences between methods with and without the bang operator.
</p>




<h2>Using <code>unless</code> and <code>until</code></h2>


<p>
  When you want to write logic when something is <i>not</i> true, you might be tempted to write code like this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">if</span> <span class="o">!</span><span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">is_legal?</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;I can&#39;t buy alcohol&quot;</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>or alternatively</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">if</span> <span class="ow">not</span> <span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">is_legal?</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;I can&#39;t buy alcohol&quot;</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  Instead of combining <code>if</code> and <code>!</code>, it is often times more intuitive to use <code>unless</code>.
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">unless</span> <span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">is_legal?</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;I can&#39;t buy alcohol&quot;</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  This sounds closer to English and is far more readable. Instead of "If current user is not legal, do this", it takes a little less mental energy if I were to say "Unless current user is legal, do this".
</p>




<p>
  Same thing with <code>while</code> loops. Instead of writing this kind of code:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">while</span> <span class="o">!</span><span class="n">fruit</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">is_ripe?</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;This fruit isn&#39;t ripe yet.&quot;</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  You could make the code much easier to mentally process by rewriting it like this:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">until</span> <span class="n">fruit</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">is_ripe?</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;This fruit isn&#39;t ripe yet.&quot;</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  It takes less mental energy to read and understand code if we use <code>unless</code> and <code>until</code> in these kinds of situations.
</p>




<h2>One Line Statements</h2>




<p>Let's say we have code written like this:</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">is_legal?</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;I can buy alcohol&quot;</span>
<span class="k">end</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>Instead of using multiple lines, we can rewrite this code in one line like this:</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;I can buy alcohol&quot;</span> <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">is_legal?</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  This applies to things like <code>unless</code> as well:
</p>


<p><figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">&quot;I can&#39;t buy alcohol&quot;</span> <span class="k">unless</span> <span class="n">current_user</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">is_legal?</span></code></pre></figure></p>

<p>
  When writing these one-liners, make sure that the line isn't too long. The point here is to make the code more readable, so you don't want to defeat the purpose by cramming a bunch of code into one line just because you can.
</p>




<hr>




<p>
  Just implementing these simple techniques will make you a better ruby programmer. Ruby offers many elegant solutions like these and learning them are really worth the time.
</p>




<p>Happy coding :)</p>

 ]]></content>
</entry>



</feed>
